[music]
>> You can see
I saw cherry right behind me and all
around.
Hello world. Japan, Japan loves sakura,
cherry blossoms. Anticipation for kaik
first bloom beats in the hearts of
residents and foreigners alike.
Everyone wants to know when spring is
here with sakura being the ultimate
symbol of rebirth, renewal and the
fleeting nature of life.
Snow may still be on the mountains, but
in the plains and valleys you can
witness the buds
>> [music]
>> ready to burst.
Sakura forecasts are a serious business
and to achieve perfection, the perfect
hanami cherry blossom viewing party, you
need to know the right time, which like
life is unpredictable, inscrutable and
requires a paid app, which I can't show
you because I'm in Japan and we get a
different free version, but I can tell
you the paid version comes with
proximity alerts to great trees.
>> Woah.
>> Lets you find your kind of pink.
>> And requires you to pay again the
following season. Wow.
So, looking for that perfect hanami, you
checked out the forecasts, chose a time
for the party and
it's still chilly outside.
Despite the blossoms getting close to
peak, the garbage bins and toilets set
up and ready to go, 60% in Japan don't
like cherry blossom viewing with
colleagues. Calls events work. But I
think this guy is doing fine.
For busy areas, it's common to stake out
your spot early on in the day with a
blue sheet, which are heavy-duty plastic
tarps you buy from home centers. Or they
could be green. I think you get the
point.
This is Ueno Park, one of the most
popular hanami spots in Tokyo. Despite
the cool, [music] cloudy weather, the
place is absolutely packed.
More and more, the sakura season in
Japan creates a huge economic boost. In
2025, an expected quarter of hanami
goers were to be foreign tourists and
because it's Japan, the economic impact
is measured to be 10 times more than
homegrown baseball star Ohtani's
previous season.
This is not only transportation costs,
but food, drinks and souvenirs, which
local retailers know all too well.
There's sakura soba, sakura flowers on
yuba, sakura onigiri, sakura [music]
pocky, sakura cupcakes, sakura buns and
on and on.
>> [music]
>> Perfect blossom is a rare thing.
You could spend your life looking for
them and it would not be a wasted life.
This is the day everyone is hoping to
get. It's clear,
>> [music]
>> it's warm and the cherry blossoms are
mankai, in full bloom.
Because mankai only last a week or
shorter and the weather is
temperamental, actually enjoying that
perfect day can be illusory. [music]
Some people even travel to different
areas across Japan trying to tilt
fortune in their favor.
As luck would have it, on March 29th,
[music] 2018, my brother and I picked a
random night to go explore one of
Tokyo's most famous cherry blossom
viewing spots, Chidorigafuchi.
I don't know if it was technically
mankai or not, but it's as close as I've
gotten in my over decade in Japan.
Out on the water, people went for the
ultimate experience, paddling among the
fallen blossoms
>> [music]
>> in the moat surrounding the Imperial
Palace.
The cost, a cool 12,000 yen for your
advanced online reservation.
However, it's completely free to walk
around and enjoy the nighttime
illumination.
Taking a mountain of pictures while
you're at the event seems mandatory.
This is one of those times where
residents and tourists alike take photos
and videos with reckless abandon. On
foot, my brother and I found the hustle
and bustle of the whole event quite fun,
but I don't think I'd ever want to lay
my blue sheet down and picnic in the
chaos.
If you feel the same as I do, you're in
luck because there are literally
thousands of other areas to have a nice
picnic where you don't have to fight for
a good spot or deal with the crowds.
For example, at Tokyo's largest park,
Mizumoto, I witnessed a few small groups
of people enjoying a lovely evening
under the blossoms.
Despite being the biggest park, it's on
the far east side of Tokyo with no
nearby train stations. So in all my
years, I've never not been able to
easily find a tree with no one else
under it.
>> [music]
>> As much as everyone wants that perfect
full bloom day, it feels like more often
than not a storm [music] hits and washes
it all away.
This gale happened the day before I was
to have a hanami party. While I was
concerned all was lost, [music]
I also dutifully braved the weather to
capture hanachirashi no ame,
flower scattering rain.
And I have to say, in its own way,
>> [music]
>> there was a beauty in the destruction.
The truth is, the only guaranteed full
bloom you could always find is in
Japan's retail machine. That's because
they have fake, fake plastic trees.
Well, fake plastic flowers wired to real
trees, but you know what I'm saying.
>> [music]
[laughter]
>> In Ginza, one of the most manufactured
places in Japan, we searched for the
calm after the storm looking for
perfection in its basement treats.
That's because of course the basements
of Japan's biggest department stores
house their ready-to-go food floors
[music] where you can skip the dishes
and satiate all your sakura food
desires.
>> [music]
>> As it turned out, even though the big
storm hit only 24 hours before, the day
of our hanami party was sunny, warm and
[music] beautiful.
While the trees were past full bloom, I
really couldn't complain. The hardest
part of the day was finding a spot,
which really wasn't that hard at all.
While I pretended to be busy at work
filming the hanami setup scenes, Ako and
Yamamoto sensei laid out the spread of
food.
Then David Chart showed up with some
extra treats.
Oh, good thing we didn't buy that.
And with the scene set, it was time to
eat, relax and enjoy.
Today we we got I guess kind of lucky
with the weather cuz yesterday it was
raining so much, oame.
It's a huge amount of rain, but we still
have some left, so.
>> Yes. So, we have a word hazakura.
>> Hazakura? Um, ha means leaves and sakura
is cherry blossoms, so even we can see
leaves, we still enjoy sakura. Cherry
blossom is a kind of symbol of start
something. Yeah. April is the month to
start everything like school or company,
so when we see sakura
cherry blossoms, we think oh, it's you
know,
start new thing.
>> [music]
>> So, cherry blossoms last only 10 days or
2 weeks. It's very short period. So,
it's kind of life. Ah, [laughter] like
life. Wow.
Perfect.
I haven't yet captured a cherry blossom
storm quite like the movie. But with any
luck, I still have many years left to
get it.
Thanks for watching. See you next time.
Peace. I hope you find that little
moment of perfection you're looking for.
Ha, [laughter] I just want to make it
clear with that music and scene, it
might look like Nyanta is no longer with
us, but he's still young and genki, so
don't worry.